Hello everyone, this is Ria!
Here is a calendar.
Calendar
What are Saturday and Sunday in Korean?
Saturday and Sunday
Yes, they are the weekend!
Weekend
Then, what are Monday through Friday in Korean?
Yes, that's right.
They are called weekdays.
Weekdays
Do you like weekdays?
Or do you like weekends?
Is there anyone here who answered "I like weekdays more!"?
Probably not.
Usually, Korean companies start work at 9 in the morning.
9 o'clock
They start at 9 and finish at 6.
Start at 9 in the morning and finish at 6 in the evening.
On Sunday night, when the weekend ends, many Koreans say this:
Ah, I don't want to go to work...
I really don't want to go to work.
"Going to work" means going to the company to work.
Going to work
To go to work.
Especially on Mondays, everyone hates going to work.
If you take the subway on Monday morning, everyone's expression is not good.
Their expressions are not good.
So in Korean, there is a word called "Monday sickness."
Monday sickness
The word "sickness" is originally used when your body is sick.
When your body is sick
But here, it's a combined word of "Monday" (wol-yo) and "sickness" (byeong).
Combined word
So what does it mean?
It means it's hard like you're sick on Monday, like you caught a disease.
It's hard.
It's said jokingly like this.
Do you remember the word we learned in the old podcast?
When talking about iPhones, we learned the word "Apple sickness."
Interestingly, in the US, they also use this word in English.
Then how about Monday sickness, everyone?
Does your language have a word like this?
If you get through Monday well, it becomes Friday.
Friday
Finally, Friday
If you work just one more day, you can rest the next day.
Finally, you can rest the next day.
The next day is the weekend.
Weekend
So everyone waits only for Friday.
They wait to leave work quickly on Friday.
Leaving work
To leave work.
Leaving work means finishing work and leaving the company.
Work is finished.
And then you go home.
This is leaving work.
But do Korean people go home after leaving work?
If they are really tired, some go home, but most go out to have fun.
In Korean, there is a word called "Bulgeum."
Burning Friday = Bulgeum
On Bulgeum, after leaving work, many people go out to have fun.
Go out to have fun.
If you look around the streets of Seoul from Friday evening, it's very crowded.
What does "bukkeok-bukkeok" mean?
"Bukkeok-bukkeok" means there are so many people that it feels noisy and crowded.
On Friday, wherever you go in Seoul, there are many people.
There are many places to have fun in Seoul on Bulgeum.
There are many places to have fun, but I usually go to Gangnam or a place called Euljiro on Bulgeum.
Gangnam and Euljiro in Korea.
These are places I like.
But these two places have very different vibes.
But I want to recommend the place called Euljiro to you all.
I want to recommend it.
In Seoul's Euljiro, you can eat outside until late at night.
Outside
I like eating outside.
You can eat outside when the weather is nice.
The atmosphere is really good.
I will tell you more about Seoul later.
But I traveled in Japan for a long time.
When I was in Japan, I met friends and had fun on Friday nights.
I met friends and had fun on Friday nights.
Japan's Bulgeum
I went out to enjoy Japan's Bulgeum.
But when I went out on Friday night, there were so many people.
It was very similar to Korea.
It was similar.
There were many people on the streets and it was very crowded.
It was very crowded.
As expected! As expected! It seems that Bulgeum is loved not only by Koreans but by everyone.
But I traveled to Japan with a Swiss friend.
But that Swiss friend was very surprised.
My Swiss friend told me that in Switzerland, there aren't this many people on Friday nights.
There aren't this many people.
How is the Bulgeum atmosphere in your country?
Is it very crowded and bustling like in Korea and Japan?
Or is it a bit quiet?
Hmm... Now I will tell you what I do on weekdays.
Weekdays
Mon Tue Wed Thu Fri = weekdays
Actually, I work both on weekdays and weekends.
I work without distinguishing between weekdays and weekends.
I work without distinguishing.
So honestly, Bulgeum doesn't feel that special to me.
It doesn't feel that special.
No matter the day, when all the work is done, that's Bulgeum for me.
It feels like Bulgeum.
A feeling of liberation!
There might be people like me whose work is not very regular.
There might be people whose work is not regular.
Work being regular means the time is fixed from Monday to Friday, 9 to 6.
When the time is fixed, we say it's "regular."
Anyway, my work is not regular, so sometimes it's hard, but there are many good times too.
I don't have Monday sickness either.
How about you?
Are you waiting for Bulgeum?
Or do you have a favorite day of the week?
Please definitely tell me what you do on Bulgeum in your country.
Also, please definitely tell me your favorite day in the comments!
If you want to study more fun with me, please click this link too.
Thank you so much for listening to my podcast today.
See you next time with a more fun podcast!
Have a good day on weekdays and weekends! Bye :)